<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorial on Arvee&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorial on Arvee&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 14:06:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Set Up GNU Radio with Docker and UHD for SDR Development</title>
      <link>/posts/gnuradiodocker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 14:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/gnuradiodocker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This guide was tested on a Linux machine (Debian 12 - Bookworm), proper, up to date system with administrative privileges for the installing user.&#xA;The following instructions are also compatible with other Debian based distributions like Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing-docker&#34;&gt;Installing Docker&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source : &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/engine/install/debian/&#34;&gt;https://docs.docker.com/engine/install/debian/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before you install Docker Engine for the first time on a new host machine, you need to set up the Docker &lt;code&gt;apt&lt;/code&gt; repository. Afterward, you can install and update Docker from the repository.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effortless Package Management: A Comprehensive Look at APT</title>
      <link>/posts/apt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 00:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/apt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You must’ve stumbled upon this command while reading online tutorials on how to install software, and we’ve all copy-pasted the command without a second thought because it works well most of the time and is an easy, convenient way to install/update software.&#xA;Today I’ll dive deeper on the intricacies of this command.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-apt-package-manager&#34;&gt;What is APT Package Manager&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/APT_%28software%29&#34;&gt;Advanced Package Tool&lt;/a&gt; (APT) is a free utility that lets user install, update and manage software packages. These packages are bundled in repositories, which are external sources containing software that users can install. APT simplifies the interaction with these repositories and automates the management of dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
